Yeah, let's discuss the program in this session.
Okay, so I'll give you each and everything how I designed this code and what the code will
be doing.
So this are the library functions we just used for the unpuking a process, and you can
see the payroll here.
So this is nothing but it will be previously I just designed with it will be opening
your message box and it will throw something, but now I just developed a shell code that
will be opening a calculator dot exe on the machine.
So this is the shell code so you can you can develop a shell code from mls of venom or
you can use other tool, other kind of tools.
So whatever shell code you are giving here, so this will be considered a payload, so
I just given the calc.exe you can develop a malicious shell code or something, and you
can test it in your test environment, okay.
So this is the VR giving more stronger powerful method to evade the antivirus software
scenario platform.
So I involved the AES encryption advanced encryption standard, the bit was two physics
bit.
So this is the key of AES algorithm that this will be used to decrypt the payload for
which we have encrypted here, okay.
So the EDRs and AV, if the EDRs and AV scanning this shell code, so it will not understand
what was hiding inside the shell, so that's the problem here, okay.
So we can easily evade the antivirus software and EDRs by these techniques.
So the next one.
So here you can find the bull AES decrypt up, so this is the entire code, this will be responsible
for decrypting the encrypted shell code in there, okay.
So let's jump on to my calling machine and let me show you some interesting thing.
I'll be giving you a few of the program, like AES encrypt.py, calc.bin and this programs, okay.
So you can execute the Python AES and calc.bin, so if you develop any kind of malicious
shell code, you can give it here instead of calc.bin, I have given the calc.bin, but if
you are developing a mal.bin, some kind of malicious shell code, you can give it here, okay.
So once you execute this, it will give you the key, okay.
So this is where we just given the AES, a advance instant based encryption, okay.
So this is the payload and calc.bin, okay, so nothing else, I just copy, paste the code
here, the payload and the key.
So this is responsible for decrypting the shell code, okay.
So the next line we can see, find a process idea, we are targeting the notepad.exe process,
so we have create tool help, 32 snapshot to identify the notepad process, okay.
So that's the entire thing here, just finding out the notepad.exe process idea, okay.
So the next one, we are going to unhook, we are developed a function for, perform unhooking
off.
So this is the heart of the program, it will be doing the unhooking, the current entity
library, and it will replace the new entity library into the memory, okay.
So this is entirely, it will be going to do, here you can see create file w, entity l path,
this line will load a fresh entity library and it will map the entity library into the file,
okay.
And so this all lines are related to mapping and if we get some kind of error, so it will
report the error to us.
So once we get everything done, once we get unhooked, the entity library and hooked the,
and once we unhook the entity library, and once we load the fresh entity library from
the disk, we are going to inject our shell code into the process notepad.exe.
So this is the line, it will be going to do inject the period into the target process.
Our target process will be the notepad, we target him, if he needs to target any other
process, you can design based on that, you can modify your program based on that, okay.
So this all are the main functions, we are going to call our, we are going to call our
specific functions individually.
So once the program gets executed, this main function will be called, and this line will
be get print, okay.
And this line will perform the, the first will be are going to perform the unhooking, unhooking
the load at the entity library from the memory and we are loading a new entity, the fresh
copy of the entity library from the disk.
So once we done that, we are going to find a process ID and we are injecting our payload,
decrypting our payload and we are injecting into that.
So I hope this program will be a little bit tricky and this, if you need to modify a bit
in the code, so this will be easy, you need to just modify the shell code so you can do
your own code here, I will be giving every resource or I am using and even the compiler
things or I am using, okay.
So let me go to the windows and let me execute this one.
So once I started executing, so it was saying, e derivation get perform, attempting to unhook
the deal and it found text.txt session and it hooked, it unhooked the entity library
completely, so the activity has been successful and so once we, this machine has a McAfee
and here is software, so now you can see the calculator has been opened, so here you can
find a notepad with the bid and payload decrypts successfully and obtained a new handle
to the process, the notepad and allocated memory inside the process notepad and it is
injected a shell code into that, okay and it created, and it executed a create remote
thread of function and now the calculator program has been opened and we are ed to play.
So let me go to the system in former and we can find out the notepad.
So this will be the fresh copy of entity library that was loaded in the system.
So I hope you have a clear understanding about what was happening in the process of loading
the entity library, fresh copy of entity library.
So this is one of the advanced techniques again and again I am seeing, so don't misuse
this program, so this is completely designed for the educational purpose.
And so use this for a interesting environment and if you are doing any kind of testing
or detection engineering related activities.
So I think we are good with this part and the next section we are going to see some kind
of registry modifications, killing defenders and a few other topics, okay.
So let's hop off from here and we will connect you in the next video and every resource
you can find it in the above link that was attached in the video.
You can use every program, okay.
So yeah, see you next moment.